#### ANITA NAIKAR

Mobile: +91-7899869617 ~ E-Mail:anitanaikar76@gmail.com

Seeking for a challenging and creative position, which utilizes my Quality and technical engineering knowledge to help in the growth of the organization

#### **Executive Summary Technical Skill Set** Having more than 4.7 years of cross cultural experiences in Aerospace & Industrial Quality **Power system** engineering and manufacturing of various products. **Engineering** Currently designated as Quality engineer at TE Connectivity, Bangalore(India), Supporting 70C Tools & 8D multiple projects by using Quality tools. **Problem Solving** Having good knowledge on HV product testing (HV & PD Testing, Air Leak testing, Pull **Working on SAP** force testing, Resistance testing, Megger testing etc). CAPA, PPAP Handled NC on Incoming, In process & Final inspection. Preparation Good Knowledge on 7QC tools, 8D problem solving methodology, CAPA, PPAP **FAI Reports** preparation. **Experience in customer complaint handling. IQC & FQC** Inspection Involved in many customer calls and successfully completed the new project. Online product quality related problem solving in production line. a **Microsoft Office** Handled scrap reduction to improve the yield of production f (Word, Excel, Power Point). Preparing FPY & PARAT for production wise. Preparation of FAI reports for various HV products. Control plan & FMEA f đ Handling PPAP during technology transfer. Manufacturing Continuous improvements through RRCA & Why-Why analysis. a **GD&T & Drawing** SAP transaction & QM lot clearance. Reading Preparation of audit checklist, Inspection reports etc a Potential problem identification & solving through FMEA & control plan. Production line monitoring & line audits. Tools, Gauge, Fixture validation. Process validation & operator approval for specific process. Working with cross functional. Weekly supplier visit. Good knowledge of quality of manufacturing.

Planning and co-ordination of day-to-day activities, Understanding project requirements, study and proposal preparation and project execution.

☐ Involved in various types of quality projects in all aspects of engineering and quality practices from part studies, creation of DOU & MOM, and development of test reports & analysis for the implementation and considering manufacturing feasibilities as well.

# **Professional Experience**

## **TE Connectivity, Bangalore**

Project Name	High Voltage products manufactring	Duration	SEPT 2021 to Till date
		Team Size	6 people
Description	High voltage Cable assembly, Jumper lead, Insulator breaker, Air feed ,Circuit breaker		
Role & Contribution	Role: Quality Inspector  Responsibilities:  Clearing the lots based on priority on daily basis.(EOU&DDS): Physical verification of the Inspection reports; SAP QA32 clearance.  Inspection of lots monitoring and clearing it.  NC handling: Raising Rework notification to Production & move the stock back to production; Document of confirm rejection location on time.  Training of Final Inspectors based on requirement  Daily FRB meeting Participating.  Weekly QCPC meeting Participating  Weekly MRB reviews  SS management at Final inspection area  Continuous Improvement to Reduce 100% Inspection based on Customer Rejection		
Client	<ul> <li>Knowledge on inspection documents as per QMS /AS Customer requirement</li> <li>Medha , Alstom , Dawosys</li> </ul>		
Tools	7QC & 8D		

## AH Electronics, Bangalore

Project Name	Aerospace Parts-Stator	Duration	June 2016 to June 2017	
		Team Size	5 people	
Description	Stator Manufacturing			
Role & Contribution	Role: QA & Production Supervisor  Responsibilities:  Potential problem identification and solving through FMEA. Production line monitoring and line audits. Preparation of audit checklists, Inspection reports, etc Rejection analysis and continuous improvement through quality tools. Customer complaint handling Work instruction review and updation through ECP and PCPN. Tool / Gauge / Fixture validation Process validation & Operator approval for specific process. Continues improvement through RRCA (Relentless root cause analysis) and 3×5 Why analysis. Handling PPAP during technology transfer. Online product quality related problem solving in Production Line. Responsible for reducing of scrap and to improve the yield of production Making reports on defects by product wise. Making reports on performance of quality Weekly presentation on defects. Supporting other teams for problem solving			
Client	Hical			

Project Name	Transformer	Duration	June 2015 to June 2017
		Team Size	5 people
Description	Transformer Manufacturing		
Role & Contribution	Role: QA & Production Supervisor  Responsibilities:  Potential problem identification and solving through FMEA. Production line monitoring and line audits. Preparation of audit checklists, Inspection reports, etc Rejection analysis and continuous improvement through quality tools. Customer complaint handling Work instruction review and updation through ECP and PCPN. Tool / Gauge / Fixture validation Process validation & Operator approval for specific process. Continues improvement through RRCA (Relentless root cause analysis) and 3×5 Why analysis.  Handling PPAP during technology transfer. Online product quality related problem solving in Production Line. Responsible for reducing of scrap and to improve the yield of production Making reports on defects by product wise. Making reports on performance of quality Weekly presentation on defects. Supporting other teams for problem solving		
Client	Hical		

Project Name	Torroids	Duration	June 2015 to June 2017
		Team Size	5 people
Description	Torroids Manufacturing		
Role & Contribution	Role: QA & Production Supervisor  Responsibilities:  Potential problem identification and solving through FMEA. Production line monitoring and line audits. Preparation of audit checklists, Inspection reports, etc Rejection analysis and continuous improvement through quality tools. Customer complaint handling Work instruction review and updation through ECP and PCPN. Tool / Gauge / Fixture validation Process validation & Operator approval for specific process. Continues improvement through RRCA (Relentless root cause analysis) and 3×5 Why analysis. Handling PPAP during technology transfer. Online product quality related problem solving in Production Line. Responsible for reducing of scrap and to improve the yield of production Making reports on defects by product wise. Making reports on performance of quality Weekly presentation on defects. Supporting other teams for problem solving		
Client	Hical		

Project Name	Surge Controller	Duration	June 2015 to June 2017
		Team Size	5 people
Description	Surge Controller Manufacturing		
Role & Contribution	Role: QA & Production Supervisor  Responsibilities:  Potential problem identification and solving through FMEA. Production line monitoring and line audits. Preparation of audit checklists, Inspection reports, etc Rejection analysis and continuous improvement through quality tools. Customer complaint handling Work instruction review and updation through ECP and PCPN. Tool / Gauge / Fixture validation Process validation & Operator approval for specific process. Continues improvement through RRCA (Relentless root cause analysis) and 3×5 Why analysis. Handling PPAP during technology transfer. Online product quality related problem solving in Production Line. Responsible for reducing of scrap and to improve the yield of production Making reports on defects by product wise. Making reports on performance of quality Weekly presentation on defects. Supporting other teams for problem solving		
Client	Hical		

#### **Academic Qualifications**

Post Graduated in Power systems Engineering from UBDT Affiliated to Visvesvaraya Technological University in the Year of 2019 with 73.0%.

Graduated in Electrical & Electronics engineering from S K S V M A C E T Affiliated to Visvesvaraya Technological University in the Year of 2015 with 72.5%.

#### **Personal Profile**

**Date of Birth** :22-01-1994

Father's Name : Chandrashekar Naikar

Address : D/O Chandrashekar.P.N

Kurthakoti(v)-582205, Tq: Gadag Dist: Gadag

Email Address :anitanaikar76@gmail.com

**Contact number** : +91 7899869617

**Hobbies** : Cooking, Gardening.

**Languages known**: English and Indian regional languages(Kannada).

I hereby declare that the above furnished details are true, to the best of my knowledge.

Bangalore (Anita Naikar)